

- Berlin, Germany
- vitalii.potapenko@gmail.com
- +49 176 214 76 461
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/ vitalii-potapenko/
- https://github.com/vitaliiptp

TECHNOLOGY STACK

HTML/CSS

JavaScript (React, NextJS, Storybook, NodeJS + Express); Python (Flask, Jupiter Notebooks); SQL (MySQL); REST APIs; Git, Unix VS Code, WebStorm, PyCharm

SIDE PROJECTS

- Analysis of the dataset using SQL and IBM Db2 on Cloud
- Analysis of the Loan dataset using classification algorithms (KNN, Decision Tree, SVM, LR)
- Tweets sentiment analysis using Twitter API and AWS cloud computing

COURSES

- Databases and SQL for Data Science (IBM specialization)
- Machine Learning with Python (IBM specialization)

LANGUAGES

English - Fluent German - B2 Russian - Native Ukrainian - Native

VITALII POTAPENKO

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

After more than 8 years in financial analysis that included building dashboards, forecasts, and custom reports with Python scripting, I've decided to focus full time on software engineering. I've successfully completed the coding Bootcamp to structure and formalize my knowledge. And now I'm looking for a web developer position.

PROJECTS

Solar System App (web app)

https://space-project-front.herokuapp.com/

Technologies: React, Bootstrap, NodeJS, Express, MySQL

Feedback App (web app)

https://wcs-final-proj.vercel.app/

Technologies: React, Tailwind, NodeJS, NextJS

Landing web page for DeFi (web app)

https://vitaliiptp.me/BlockchainWebpage/

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap

Web app for musicians (web app)

https://github.com/vitaliiptp/jam-project-front https://github.com/vitaliiptp/jam-project-back

Technologies: React, Bootstrap, NodeJS, Express, Mysql

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sr Financial Analyst

HERE Technologies GmbH, Berlin | Feb 2020 - Jun 2021

Accountant

GetYourGuide GmbH, Berlin | Dec 2018 - Feb 2020

Sr Financial Reporting Specialist

JSC Kyivstar (Veon Group), Kyiv | Sep 2012 - Sep 2016

Financial Reporting Specialist

JSC Ukrsibbank (BNP Paribas Group), Kyiv | Mar 2010 - Sep 2012

EDUCATION

Wild Code School Bootcamp

Full-Time Programm | Sep 2021 - Feb 2022 Full-Stack Web Development Program

EPAM University

Course | Feb 2021 - Jun 2021

Full-Stack Web Development Program

Free University Berlin

MA | Oct 2016 - Oct 2018

Social Sciences (Economics & Political science)

Kyiv National Economic University

MSc | Sep 2004 - Jun 2009

Business Economics